<?xml version='1.0'?><script><version>1/24/07 2e</version><page><paragraph time='timecode' speaker='professor' graphic-file='AMW01G1-s.jpg'>I'm going to talk now about the missing colonists from Roanoke and the theory expressed in the reading passage about their eventual fate. Please note that what is in the reading passage is only a theory, one of many theories, actually. And there are some pretty good reasons for thinking that the theory expressed in the reading passage is not the most credible theory. Let me talk now about some reasons why I say this.<br/><br/>First of all, Croatan Island has been searched thoroughly and repeatedly for any possible remnants of the colonists from Roanoke Island. In these numerous and in-depth searches of Croatan Island, not a single trace of the colonists from Roanoke Island has been found. You would think there would be some evidence if the colonists had ever been there, but there is no such evidence at all.<br/><br/>Now for a second reason why the theory expressed in the reading passage might not be the best theory. According to the theory in the reading passage, the colonists must have gone to Croatan Island because they left carvings with "Cro" and "Croatan" before they left Roanoke Island. But Croatan is not just the name of an island. Other locations and tribes on the mainland are called Croatan.<br/><br/>A third and very interesting reason why the theory expressed in the reading passage might not be true is related to something unexpected that was found 200 years after the Roanoke colonists disappeared. In the eighteenth century, explorers came across an unusual tribe of people on the American mainland, inland from Roanoke Island. This tribe lived on the Lumber River and were sometimes called Croatans. This tribe was unusual in that members of the tribe spoke English and were able to read and write in English and also because some had blond hair and blue eyes instead of the darker features that were common in other native tribes. The existence of this tribe in the inland area of the mainland suggests that perhaps the missing settlers from Roanoke had moved inland from the island and intermixed with the native tribe there.</paragraph></page></script>