<?xml version='1.0'?><passage><version>1/24/07 2e file</version><passage-text>A.O. Smith Corporation is a company that produces car frames and then sells them to major car manufacturers to use in producing cars. In the early 1980s, A.O. Smith wanted to increase the company's productivity, so it decided to introduce a new wage system.<br/>The new wage system introduced in the early 1980s to increase productivity was a piecework wage system. In a piecework wage system, each worker is paid based upon the number of pieces produced. A worker who produces a lot of pieces will receive a higher paycheck, and a worker who produces a lower number of pieces will receive a lower paycheck.<br/>One outcome that the company expected from this new system was that productivity would increase. It was believed that, if pay was based on the number of pieces a worker produced, then each worker would work hard to produce a lot of pieces. It seemed logical to expect that productivity would increase when a worker's pay was based on the number of pieces produced.<br/>The company also expected morale to increase when the new system was introduced. The company was not interested in increasing productivity if the workers' morale suffered as a result. However, under a system where workers were able to increase their pay by increasing their productivity, company managment expected morale to improve. It seemed equally logical to the company that morale would be really high among workers who were able to increase their pay by producing at a higher rate.<br/>Soon after implementing the new piecework wage system, A.O. Smith was initially quite pleased with the results. The immediate results were that both productivity and morale increased. Workers produced more car frames than they had previously produced because of the way pay was determined, and workers were more satisfied with their jobs because their pay was increasing. These results were logically expected outcomes of the implementation of such a system.</passage-text></passage>